There are worlds beyond our own. The compass will show the way.
The Golden Compass is a adventure, fantasy film directed by Chris Weitz.
In a parallel universe, after overhearing a shocking secret, precocious orphan Lyra Belacqua trades her carefree existence roaming
the halls of Jordan College for an otherworldly adventure in the far North, unaware that it's part of her destiny.
Marisa Coulter, played by Nicole Kidman.
Lord Asriel, played by Daniel Craig.
Lyra Belacqua, played by Dakota Blue Richards.
Roger Parslow, played by Ben Walker.
Pantalaimon (voice), played by Freddie Highmore.
Iorek Byrnison (voice), played by Ian McKellen.
The Golden Compass is a 2007 fantasy adventure film written and directed by Chris
Weitz, based  on the 1995 novel Northern Lights by Philip Pullman.
It stars Nicole Kidman, Sam Elliott, Eva Green,
Dakota Blue Richards and Daniel Craig.
In the film, Lyra joins a race of water-workers and seafarers on a trip to the far North in search of
children kidnapped by the Gobblers, a group supported by the world's rulers, the Magisterium.
Development on the film was announced in February 2002, but difficulties over the screenplay and the
selection of a director (including Weitz departing and returning) caused significant delays.
Richards was cast as Lyra in June 2006, with Kidman
and Craig joining soon thereafter.
Principal photography began that September at Shepperton
Studios and lasted for several months.
Location filming also took place in England, Switzerland, and Norway.
The Golden Compass premiered in London on 27 November 2007, and was theatrically released in the United Kingdom
by Entertainment Film on 5 December and in the United States by New Line Cinema on 7 December.
The film received mixed reviews and grossed $372
million against a budget of $180 million.
It won Best Visual Effects at the 80th Academy Awards and Best Special
Visual Effects at the 61st British Academy Film Awards.
The film explores themes of compass, experiment, england, polar bear, airship.